<node name="/node" xmlns:tp="http://telepathy.freedesktop.org/wiki/DbusSpec#extensions-v0">

<tp:title>AT-SPI - Assistive Technology Service Provider Interface </tp:title>
<tp:copyright>Copyright 2008 Novell, Inc.</tp:copyright>
<tp:copyright>Copyright 2001 Sun Microsystems, Inc.</tp:copyright>
<tp:license xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <p>This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or
    modify it under the terms of the GNU Library General Public
    License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either
    version 2 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.</p>

  <p>This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
    but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
    MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU
    Library General Public License for more details.</p>

  <p>You should have received a copy of the GNU Library General Public
    License along with this library; if not, write to the
    Free Software Foundation, Inc., 59 Temple Place - Suite 330,
    Boston, MA 02111-1307, USA.</p>
</tp:license>
<interface name="org.freedesktop.accessibility.Value">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>An interface supporting controls which allow a
      one-dimensional, scalar quantity to be modified or which
      reflect a scalar quantity. (If STATE_EDITABLE is not present, 
      the valuator is treated as &quot;read only&quot;.  </p>

    <p>@note Events generated by Image instances include:
      \li \c &quot;object:value-changed&quot;</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  <tp:property name="minimumValue" type="d" access="read">
  <tp:docstring>
    The minimum value allowed by this valuator.
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:property>
  <tp:property name="maximumValue" type="d" access="read">
  <tp:docstring>
    The maximum value allowed by this valuator.
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:property>
  <tp:property name="minimumIncrement" type="d" access="read">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>The smallest incremental change which this valuator allows.
      If 0, the incremental changes to the valuator are 
      limited only by the precision of a double precision value
      on the platform.</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:property>
  <tp:property name="currentValue" type="d" access="readwrite">
  <tp:docstring>
    The current value of the valuator.
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:property>
  <method name="unImplemented">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>\cond
        unImplemented:    </p>

      <p>placeholders for future expansion.</p>
    </tp:docstring>
  </method>
  <method name="unImplemented2">
  </method>
  <method name="unImplemented3">
  </method>
  <method name="unImplemented4">
  </method>
</interface>
</node>
