<node name="/node" xmlns:tp="http://telepathy.freedesktop.org/wiki/DbusSpec#extensions-v0">

<tp:title>AT-SPI - Assistive Technology Service Provider Interface </tp:title>
<tp:copyright>Copyright 2008 Novell, Inc.</tp:copyright>
<tp:copyright>Copyright 2001 Sun Microsystems Inc.</tp:copyright>
<tp:license xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
  <p>This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or
    modify it under the terms of the GNU Library General Public
    License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either
    version 2 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.</p>

  <p>This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
    but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
    MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU
    Library General Public License for more details.</p>

  <p>You should have received a copy of the GNU Library General Public
    License along with this library; if not, write to the
    Free Software Foundation, Inc., 59 Temple Place - Suite 330,
    Boston, MA 02111-1307, USA.</p>
</tp:license>
<interface name="org.freedesktop.accessibility.Registry">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>The Registry is a service through which applications providing 
      accessibility services (servers) can rendezvous with consumers of those
      services (Assistive Technologies).  The Registry is the first &quot;port of call&quot; for 
      accessible applications and for assistive technologies wishing to query and
      interact with those applications.  </p>

    <p>The Registry service provides four basic functions to Assistive Technology (AT) clients:
      \li it provides a list of the applications who have registered with the AT-SPI
      framework, thereby announcing their participation in the AT-SPI framework;
      \li it allows AT clients to register for notification of changes in application
      state (at-spi Events);
      \li it dispatches/relays said events from participating applications to
      the registered listeners;
      \li it gives access to system device events via the associated DeviceEventController
      interface.  </p>

    <p>From the point of view of accessible applications (i.e. AT-SPI service producers), 
      the Registry is primarily a registration and event delivery service.  Applications 
      normally only call the registerApplication and deregisterApplication Registry methods,
      and its inherited EventListener::notifyEvent method.  </p>

    <p>@note Although all application events are dispatched via the Registry, other AT client 
      calls are serviced directly by the applications, rather than being relayed via the
      Registry.  The AT client obtains references to these application objects
      via the enumeration of Desktop instances whose children are Application instances
      (Registry::getDesktopList) and via examination of the 'source' member of the Event 
      structure.   </p>

    <p>The Registry normally lives in its own process space; communication via Registry and
      both application services and AT clients takes place via IPC.  A process space diagram
      illustrating the relationship between applications, Registry, and AT is shown below.
      @image html &quot;http://developer.gnome.org/projects/gap/tech-docs/SPIBlockDiagram.png&quot;  </p>

    <p>@see Desktop, Application, Event, EventListener</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  <method name="registerApplication">
    <tp:docstring>
      Register a new application with the accessibility broker.
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="in" name="app" type="o" tp:type="Application">
    <tp:docstring>
      a reference to the requesting Application
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="deregisterApplication">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>De-register an application previously registered with the broker.
        deregisterApplication:</p>
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="in" name="app" type="o" tp:type="Application">
    <tp:docstring>
      a reference to the Application to be deregistered.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="registerGlobalEventListener">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>Register a client's interest in (all) application events of 
        a certain type.</p>
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="in" name="listener" type="o" tp:type="EventListener">
    <tp:docstring>
      a reference to the requesting ::EventListener.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="in" name="eventName" type="s">
    <tp:docstring>
      a string which indicates the type of events about which the client desires notification.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="deregisterGlobalEventListenerAll">
    <tp:docstring>
      deregisterGlobalEventListenerAll:
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="in" name="listener" type="o" tp:type="EventListener">
    <tp:docstring>
      the requesting EventListenerRequest that a previously registered client stop receivingglobal notifications for all events for which it was registered.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="deregisterGlobalEventListener">
    <tp:docstring>
      deregisterGlobalEventListener:
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="in" name="listener" type="o" tp:type="EventListener">
    <tp:docstring>
      the requesting EventListener
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="in" name="eventName" type="s">
    <tp:docstring>
      a string indicating the type of eventsRequest that a previously registered client stop receivingglobal notifications for events of a certain type.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="getDesktopCount">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>event types: &quot;Window&quot; &quot;Desktop&quot;
        &quot;Window:Create&quot; &quot;Window:Destroy&quot;
        &quot;Window:Iconify&quot; &quot;Window:Restore&quot;
        &quot;Window:Fullscreen&quot; &quot;Window:Resize&quot;
        &quot;Desktop:Create&quot; &quot;Desktop:Destroy&quot;  
        &quot;Desktop:Focus&quot; &quot;Desktop:Defocus&quot;
        &quot;Desktop:Reorder&quot; 
        &quot;Focus&quot;
        &quot;GtkWidget:show&quot;
        &quot;GObject:notify:&lt;propertyname&gt;&quot;     </p>

      <p>( not sure we should allow these last 2 forms, 
        since they are toolkit-specific, but they're powerful )    </p>

      <p>getDesktopCount:    </p>

      <p>Get the current number of desktops.</p>
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="out" type="n" tp:type="short">
    <tp:docstring>
      a short integer indicating the current number of Desktops.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="getDesktop">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>getDesktop:
        @n: the index of the requested Desktop.    </p>

      <p>Get the nth accessible desktop.     </p>
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="in" name="n" type="n" tp:type="short"/>
    <arg direction="out" type="o" tp:type="Desktop">
    <tp:docstring>
      a reference to the requested Desktop.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="getDesktopList">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>Get a list of accessible desktops.     </p>
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="out" type="ao" tp:type="DesktopSeq">
    <tp:docstring>
      a sequence containing references tothe Desktops.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="getDeviceEventController">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>Obtain an object which can be used to request device event notifications.    </p>
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="out" type="o" tp:type="DeviceEventController">
    <tp:docstring>
      an object implementing DeviceEventController
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="unImplemented">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>\cond
        unImplemented:    </p>

      <p>placeholders for future expansion.</p>
    </tp:docstring>
  </method>
  <method name="unImplemented2">
  </method>
  <method name="unImplemented3">
  </method>
  <method name="unImplemented4">
  </method>
  <method name="unImplemented5">
  </method>
  <method name="unImplemented6">
  </method>
</interface>
<tp:enum name="KeyEventType" type="u">
  <tp:docstring>
    Deprecated, DO NOT USE! 
  </tp:docstring>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="KEY_PRESSED"/>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="KEY_RELEASED" value="1"/>
</tp:enum>
<tp:enum name="EventType" type="u">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>Used to specify the event types of interest to an EventListener, or
      to identify the type of an event for which notification has been sent. 
      @see EventTypeSeq, DeviceEvent::type</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="KEY_PRESSED_EVENT">
  <tp:docstring>
    &lt; key on a keyboard device was pressed. 
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="KEY_RELEASED_EVENT" value="1">
  <tp:docstring>
    &lt; key on a keyboard device was released. 
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="BUTTON_PRESSED_EVENT" value="2">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>&lt; button on a non-keyboard human interface device 
      (HID) was pressed </p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="BUTTON_RELEASED_EVENT" value="3">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>&lt; button on a non-keyboard human interface device 
      (HID) was pressed </p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
</tp:enum>
<tp:enum name="KeySynthType" type="u">
  <tp:docstring>
    Used when synthesizing keyboard input via DeviceEventController:generateKeyboardEvent.
  </tp:docstring>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="KEY_PRESS">
  <tp:docstring>
    emulate the pressing of a hardware keyboard key. 
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="KEY_RELEASE" value="1">
  <tp:docstring>
    emulate the release of a hardware keyboard key. 
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="KEY_PRESSRELEASE" value="2">
  <tp:docstring>
    a hardware keyboard key is pressed and immediately released. 
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="KEY_SYM" value="3">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>a symbolic key event is generated, without specifying a hardware key. 
      @note if the keysym is not present in the current keyboard map,
      the DeviceEventController instance has a limited ability to generate
      such keysyms on-the-fly.  Reliability of generateKeyboardEvent calls
      using out-of-keymap keysyms will vary from system to system, and on the
      number of different out-of-keymap being generated in quick succession.
      In practice this is rarely significant, since the keysyms of interest to
      AT clients and keyboard emulators are usually part of the current keymap, i.e.
      present on the system keyboard for the current locale (even if a physical
      hardware keyboard is not connected.</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="KEY_STRING" value="4">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>a string is converted to its equivalent keyboard events and emitted. 
      If the string consists of complex character or composed characters
      which are not in the current keymap, string emission is subject to the
      out-of-keymap limitations described for KeySynthType::KEY_SYM.
      In practice this limitation primarily effects Chinese and Japanese locales.</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
</tp:enum>
<tp:enum name="ModifierType" type="u">
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="MODIFIER_SHIFT">
  <tp:docstring>
    The left or right 'Shift' key 
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="MODIFIER_SHIFTLOCK" value="1">
  <tp:docstring>
    The ShiftLock or CapsLock key 
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="MODIFIER_CONTROL" value="2">
  <tp:docstring>
    'Control'/'Ctrl' 
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="MODIFIER_ALT" value="3">
  <tp:docstring>
    The Alt key (as opposed to AltGr) 
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="MODIFIER_META" value="4">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>depending on the platform this may map to 'Window', 'Function', 'Meta',
      'Menu', or 'NumLock'.  
      Such 'Meta keys' will map to one of META, META2, META3.
      On X Windows platforms these META values map to 
      the modifier masks Mod1Mask, Mod2Mask, Mod3Mask, e.g. an event having
      ModifierType::MODIFIER_META2 means that the 'Mod2Mask' bit is
      set in the corresponding XEvent.</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="MODIFIER_META2" value="5"/>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="MODIFIER_META3" value="6"/>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="MODIFIER_NUMLOCK" value="7">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>A symbolic meta key name that is mapped by AT-SPI to the 
      appropriate META value, for the convenience of the client.</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
</tp:enum>
<tp:struct name="EventListenerMode">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>A structure that encapsulates the characteristics of the event notifications
      that should be sent to an EventListener in response to a call to
      DeviceEventController::registerKeystrokeListener or 
      DeviceEventController::registerDeviceEventListener. </p>
  </tp:docstring>
  <tp:member type="b" tp:name="synchronous">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>&lt; If \c True, specifies that
      DeviceEventController should block while waiting 
      for client to process the requested event notifications; 
      ordinarily should be used only when client needs to perform
      operations synchronously with event delivery. Note that because
      of the architecture of device event systems in general,
      use of this flag may not block delivery of the event to 
      the currently focussed application unless it is used in 
      conjunction with the preemptive flag. </p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:member>
  <tp:member type="b" tp:name="preemptive">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>&lt; If \c True, specifies that 
      Listener is allowed to pre-empt the delivery of the event,
      effectively &quot;consuming&quot; it such that it is not delivered 
      to the currently focussed desktop application. 
      Key events consumed via this API will not be 
      available for use by other applications or services, so this
      option should be used sparingly. </p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:member>
  <tp:member type="b" tp:name="global">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>&lt; If \c True, specifies that
      Event notifications should be sent regardless of whether the
      currently focussed application participates in the AT-SPI 
      infrastructure.  On systems with the XEvIE X extension, this flag
      also allows access to events which are already subject to 
      interception via a &quot;system keygrab&quot; (as described in the X Window System
      documentation for XGrabKey).  The 'global' and 'preemptive' flags
      should only be used together for the purposes of registering
      &quot;system global key shortcuts&quot; i.e. command keys for use by the
      assistive technology. </p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:member>
</tp:struct>
<tp:struct name="DeviceEvent">
  <tp:docstring>
    A structure which encapsulates information about a device event. 
  </tp:docstring>
  <tp:member type="u" tp:name="type">
  <tp:docstring>
    &lt; Identifies the type of the containing DeviceEvent. 
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:member>
  <tp:member type="i" tp:name="id">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>&lt; an identifier which identifies this event in the event stream. 
      On X Window systems this corresponds to the XEvent serial number.</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:member>
  <tp:member type="n" tp:name="hw_code">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>&lt; a numeric code which is hardware and system-dependent, identifying the
      specific hardware button or key on the device for which the event has
      occurred. On X Window systems, for global key notifications and for most
      non-global key notifications as well, this code corresponds to the
      XKeycode.  For switch and button events it indicates the switch
      or button number.
      @note
      For technical reasons, this code may differ from the XKeycode
      when generated by Java applications for consumption by non-global
      key listeners.  This is subject to change in future versions of the
      DeviceEventController implementation.</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:member>
  <tp:member type="n" tp:name="modifiers">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>&lt; an unsigned short int consisting of zero or more of the following
      values OR'ed together:
      \li \c 1&lt;&lt;::MODIFIER_SHIFT   (=1, corresponds to Xlib's ShiftMask)
      \li \c 1&lt;&lt;::MODIFIER_SHIFTLOCK    (=2, corresponds to Xlib's LockMask)
      \li \c 1&lt;&lt;::MODIFIER_CONTROL (=4, corresponds to Xlib's ControlMask)
      \li \c 1&lt;&lt;::MODIFIER_ALT    (=8, corresponds to Xlib's Mod1Mask)
      \li \c 1&lt;&lt;::MODIFIER_META    (=16, corresponds to Xlib's Mod2Mask)
      \li \c 1&lt;&lt;::MODIFIER_META2    (=32, corresponds to Xlib's Mod3Mask)
      \li \c 1&lt;&lt;::MODIFIER_META3    (=64, corresponds to Xlib's Mod4Mask)</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:member>
  <tp:member type="i" tp:name="timestamp">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>&lt; an unsigned integer representing the time that the 
      event occurred.  On X Window systems this event is 
      a time in milliseconds from some arbitrary starting
      point; it therefore has a cycle time of approximately
      50 days.</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:member>
  <tp:member type="s" tp:name="event_string">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>&lt; A string representation of the event.  If is_text is
      \c True, then this string represents the character or typographic
      sequence that would be received by a focussed text input field.
      event_string is in general suitable for exposure to the
      end-user for purposes of keyboard echo.</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:member>
  <tp:member type="b" tp:name="is_text">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>&lt; \c True if the event results in the insertion of characters 
      into an input text buffer, or would do so if delivered to a focussed
      text input field. ¨Typographical¨ key events have this field set to
      \c True, whereas ¨control¨ key events generally do not.</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:member>
</tp:struct>
<tp:struct name="KeyDefinition">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>A structure which defines the identity of a key for which notifications
      are to be requested.  The data in the members of a ::KeyDefinition are used to
      determine which keyboard events 'match' the notification request filed by a client.  </p>

    <p>@note Ordinarily a KeyDefinition specifies one and only one of the criteria below; 
      the result of using a KeyDefinition with multiple members defined as nonzero is
      undefined.  </p>

    <p>@param keycode if nonzero, the numeric, system-dependent value corresponding to a 
      physical key on the keyboard.  Keycode values have no semantic meaning to the end-user,
      and may depend on the user's hardware and operating environment.  They therefore are
      rarely useful &quot;as-is&quot; to AT clients, unless the client has used operating system
      services to identify the hardward keycode associated with a particular key symbol.
      Notifications for key events requested by keycode are less dependent on modifier state
      than \c keysym based notifications, but some hardware (notably many laptops) may generate
      more than one keycode for the same physical key, depending on the state of physical 
      shift/modifier keys.
      @param keysym if nonzero, the numeric value corresponding to the X Keysym of the key for which 
      notification is requested.  Note that the presence of active modifiers will affect
      whether notification for key events requested via &quot;keysym&quot; specification takes place, 
      since the keysym depends on the modifier state for most keys.
      @param keystring if non-NULL, the string value of the inserted characters if the corresponding
      key event has ::KeyEvent:is_text set to \c True, or the string representing the
      'name' of the key.  On X11 systems, the string 'name' of non-printing keysyms corresponds
      to the values in &quot;keysymdef.h&quot; as provided by Xlib, with the leading &quot;XK_&quot; stripped off.</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  <tp:member type="i" tp:name="keycode"/>
  <tp:member type="i" tp:name="keysym"/>
  <tp:member type="s" tp:name="keystring"/>
  <tp:member type="i" tp:name="unused"/>
</tp:struct>
<interface name="org.freedesktop.accessibility.DeviceEventListener">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>This interface should be implemented by AT-SPI clients who wish to 
      make use of the DeviceEventController to receive device event notifications.
      DeviceEvents include keyboard events and mouse button/motion events.</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  <method name="notifyEvent">
    <tp:docstring>
      Notify an interested DeviceEventListener that a DeviceEvent has occurred.
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="in" name="event" type="(uinnisb)" tp:type="DeviceEvent"/>
    <arg direction="out" type="b" tp:type="boolean">
    <tp:docstring>
      \c True if the recipient/consumer wishes to consume the event, i.e.prevent it from being delivered to the desktop, \c False if the event should continue to be delivered as normal.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="unImplemented__">
    <tp:docstring>
      \cond 
    </tp:docstring>
  </method>
  <method name="unImplemented_2_">
  </method>
  <method name="unImplemented_3_">
  </method>
  <method name="unImplemented_4_">
  </method>
  <method name="unImplemented_5_">
  </method>
  <method name="unImplemented_6_">
  </method>
</interface>
<interface name="org.freedesktop.accessibility.DeviceEventController">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>The interface via which clients request notification of device events, and
      through which device events may be simulated.</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  <method name="registerKeystrokeListener">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>Register to intercept keyboard events, and either pass them on or
        consume them.     </p>
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="in" name="listener" type="o" tp:type="DeviceEventListener">
    <tp:docstring>
      a DeviceEventListener which will intercept key events.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="in" name="keys" type="a(iisi)" tp:type="KeySet">
    <tp:docstring>
      a KeySet indicating which keys to intercept, or KEYSET_ALL_KEYS.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="in" name="mask" type="u" tp:type="ControllerEventMask">
    <tp:docstring>
      a ControllerEventMask filtering the intercepted key events.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="in" name="type" type="au" tp:type="KeyEventTypeSeq">
    <tp:docstring>
      a KeyEventTypeSeq that may created by ORing event types together.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="in" name="mode" type="(bbb)" tp:type="EventListenerMode">
    <tp:docstring>
      an EventListenerMode indicating whether the listener should receive the events synchronously, potentially consuming them,or just be notified asynchronously of those events that havebeen generated.@note Some platforms have limited support for global, preemptive EventListenerMode.Such a registration may fail if another client already has priority for preemptiveaccess to one or more of the members of the KeySet.  AT consumers have the optionof re-trying the request without the global flag, or without the preemptive flag,or of re-trying with a different KeySet.  The best support for pre-emptiveglobal keyboard listeners is provided on platforms whose Xserver implementationprovides the XEvIE extension.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="out" type="b" tp:type="boolean">
    <tp:docstring>
      \c True if the DeviceEventListener was successfully registeredfor the requested KeySet, ControllerEventMask, event types, and EventListenerMode; otherwise returns \c False.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="deregisterKeystrokeListener">
    <tp:docstring>
      De-register a previously registered keyboard eventlistener.
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="in" name="listener" type="o" tp:type="DeviceEventListener">
    <tp:docstring>
      a DeviceEventListener which will intercept key events.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="in" name="keys" type="a(iisi)" tp:type="KeySet">
    <tp:docstring>
      a KeySet indicating which keys to intercept, or KEYSET_ALL_KEYS.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="in" name="mask" type="u" tp:type="ControllerEventMask">
    <tp:docstring>
      a ControllerEventMask filtering the intercepted key events.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="in" name="type" type="au" tp:type="KeyEventTypeSeq">
    <tp:docstring>
      an EventType mask that may created by ORing event types together.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="registerDeviceEventListener">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>Register to intercept events, and either pass them on or
        consume them. To listen to keyboard events use registerKeystrokeListener
        instead.</p>
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="in" name="listener" type="o" tp:type="DeviceEventListener">
    <tp:docstring>
      a DeviceEventListener which will intercept events.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="in" name="typeseq" type="au" tp:type="EventTypeSeq">
    <tp:docstring>
      an EventTypeSeq indicating which event types to listen for.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="out" type="b" tp:type="boolean">
    <tp:docstring>
      \c True if successful, \c False if not
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="deregisterDeviceEventListener">
    <tp:docstring>
      De-register a previously registered keyboard eventlistener.
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="in" name="listener" type="o" tp:type="DeviceEventListener">
    <tp:docstring>
      a DeviceEventListener which will intercept events.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="in" name="typeseq" type="au" tp:type="EventTypeSeq">
    <tp:docstring>
      an EventTypeSeq indicating which event types to stoplistening for.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="notifyListenersSync">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>Notify the Registry instance that a device event has taken place, and
        allow pre-emptive listeners the opportunity to 'consume' the event
        and thus prevent its further issuance/forwarding.  This is the 
        method used by accessibility bridges to forward &quot;toolkit dependent&quot;
        device events to the Registry from the application's process space.    </p>

      <p>@note AT clients do not normally need to use this method, it is intended for use
        by toolkit bridges and special-purpose applications.    </p>
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="in" name="event" type="(uinnisb)" tp:type="DeviceEvent"/>
    <arg direction="out" type="b" tp:type="boolean">
    <tp:docstring>
      \c True if the event was consumed by a (pre-emptive) listener,\c False if not (in which case the device event will be forwardedas normal to any application which would normally receive it, e.g.the currently active application in the case of mouse or keyboard events).
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="notifyListenersAsync">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>Notify the Registry instance that a device event has taken place in
        an asynchronous manner.  This is the 
        method used by accessibility bridges to forward &quot;toolkit dependent&quot;
        device events to the Registry from the application's process space.
        If the event in question is potentially pre-emptible.
        ::notifyListenersSync should be used instead.    </p>

      <p>@note AT clients do not normally need to use this method, it is intended for use
        by toolkit bridges and special-purpose applications.</p>
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="in" name="event" type="(uinnisb)" tp:type="DeviceEvent"/>
  </method>
  <method name="generateKeyboardEvent">
    <tp:docstring>
      Synthesize a keyboard event.
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="in" name="keycode" type="i">
    <tp:docstring>
      a long integer indicating the keycode ofthe keypress to be synthesized.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="in" name="keystring" type="s">
    <tp:docstring>
      an optional UTF-8 string indicating a complexkeyboard input event.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="in" name="type" type="u" tp:type="KeySynthType">
    <tp:docstring>
      a KeySynthType indicating the type of event(s) to be synthesized: a key press, release, press-release pair,or a complex input string (for instance from aninternationalized or complex text input method, ora composed character).@note keycode may be truncated before beingprocessed, as keycode length may be platform-dependentand keycode ranges are generally much smaller thanCORBA_long. One or the other of keycode or keystring are generally NULL, (but not both), depending on the value of \c type.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="generateMouseEvent">
    <tp:docstring>
      Synthesize a mouse event.
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="in" name="x" type="i">
    <tp:docstring>
      a long integer indicating the screen x coord for the mouse event.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="in" name="y" type="i">
    <tp:docstring>
      a long integer indicating the screen y coord for the mouse event.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="in" name="eventName" type="s">
    <tp:docstring>
      a string indicating the type of mouse event, e.g. &quot;button1up&quot;
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="unImplemented">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>\cond
        unImplemented:    </p>

      <p>placeholders for future expansion.</p>
    </tp:docstring>
  </method>
  <method name="unImplemented2">
  </method>
  <method name="unImplemented3">
  </method>
  <method name="unImplemented4">
  </method>
</interface>
</node>
