<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<node xmlns:tp="http://telepathy.freedesktop.org/wiki/DbusSpec#extensions-v0" name="/node">
<interface name="org.freedesktop.atspi.Image">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>An interface implemented by objects which render image data or 
      pictorial information to the screen.  When onscreen components include
      graphical information that is not purely intended to enhance "3d effect"
      or visual layout, but which conveys some semantic or informational 
      content to the sighted user, they should implement Image, and that 
      semantic content should be conveyed textually to the extent possible 
      via the image description, as well as the Accessible.name and 
      Accessible.description properties.  </p>
  </tp:docstring>
  <tp:property name="imageDescription" type="s" access="read">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>A UTF-8 string providing a textual description
      of what is visually depicted in the image.  </p>

    <p>It is recommended that imageDescription be the shorter
      of the available image descriptions, for instance "alt text"
      in HTML images, and a longer description be provided in
      Accessible.description, if available.
      A short, one or two word label for the image should be provided in
      Accessible.name.</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:property>
  <tp:property name="imageLocale" type="s" access="read">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>A string corresponding to the POSIX LC_MESSAGES locale used 
      by the imageDescription.</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:property>
  <method name="getImageExtents">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>Obtain a bounding box which entirely contains the image contents,
        as displayed on screen.  The bounds returned do not account for
        any viewport clipping or the fact that the image may be
        partially or wholly obscured by other onscreen content.
      </p>
      <p>This method returns the bounds of the current onscreen
        view, and not the nominal size of the source data in the
        event that the original image has been rescaled.    </p>
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="in" name="coordType" type="n" tp:type="short">
	    <tp:docstring>
      <p>If 0, the returned bounding box position is returned
        relative to the screen; if 1, the bounding box position is returned 
        relative to the containing window.</p>
	    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="out" type="(iiii)" tp:type="BoundingBox">
    <tp:docstring>
      A BoundingBox enclosing the image's onscreen representation.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="getImagePosition">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>Get the coordinates of the current image position on screen.    </p>

    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="out" name="x" type="i">
    	<tp:docstring>
        Back-filled with the x coordinate of the 
        onscreen image (i.e. the minimum x coordinate)
    	</tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="out" name="y" type="i">
    	<tp:docstring>
        Back-filled with the y coordinate of the 
        onscreen image (i.e. the minimum y coordinate)
    	</tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="in" name="coordType" type="n" tp:type="short">
    	<tp:docstring>
        If 0, the returned x and y coordinates are 
        returned relative to the screen; 
        if 1, they are returned relative to the containing window.
    	</tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="getImageSize">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>Obtain the width and height of the current onscreen view of the
        image.  The extents returned do not account for
        any viewport clipping or the fact that the image may be
        partially or wholly obscured by other onscreen content.
      </p>
      <p>This method returns the size of the current onscreen
        view, and not the nominal or "original" size of the source 
	image, in the event that the original image has been rescaled.
      </p>

    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="out" name="width" type="i">
	    <tp:docstring>
        Back-filled with the x extents of the 
        onscreen image (i.e. the image width in pixels)
	    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="out" name="height" type="i">
	    <tp:docstring>
        Back-filled with the y extents of the 
        onscreen image (i.e. the image height in pixels)
	    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
</interface>
</node>
