<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<node xmlns:tp="http://telepathy.freedesktop.org/wiki/DbusSpec#extensions-v0" name="/node">
<interface name="org.freedesktop.atspi.Application">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>An interface identifying an object which is the root of the
      user interface Accessible hierarchy associated with a running application.
      Children of Application are typically, but not exclusively, 
      top-level windows.</p>
      
    <p>It is possible for an element deeper in an Accessibility stack to
      implement Application, for instance in the case of "embedded applications"
      which draw into toplevel windows associated with other applications
      from the user's point of view.</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  <tp:property name="toolkitName" type="s" access="read">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>A string indicating the type of user interface toolkit
       which is used by the application.</p>
      <p>Ordinarily clients of the Application should be
      toolkit-agnostic, dependencies on this property should
      be avoided where possible.</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:property>
  <tp:property name="version" type="s" access="read">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>A string indicating the version number of the application's
      accessibility bridge implementation.</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:property>
  <tp:property name="id" type="i" access="readwrite">
  <tp:docstring>
    The application instance's unique ID as assigned by the registry.
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:property>
  <method name="registerToolkitEventListener">
    <arg direction="in" name="listener" type="o" tp:type="EventListener">
    <tp:docstring>
      An EventListener object which will receive the requestedevents from the application's toolkits via toolit 'bridges'
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="in" name="eventName" type="s">
    <tp:docstring>
	    <p> A UTF-8 string indicating the type of (toolkit-specific) eventbeing requested.  Not all applications can generate toolkit events of a given type. Register with this application's toolkit for "toolkit-specific" event notifications.</p>
	    
	    <p>For most event support, clients should use non-toolkit-specific events whenever possible, Registry.registerGlobalEventListener - this method is provided as a 'back door' when generic names do not exist for the events in question.</p>
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="registerObjectEventListener">
    <arg direction="in" name="listener" type="o" tp:type="EventListener">
    <tp:docstring>
      An EventListener object which will receive the requested events
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="in" name="eventName" type="s">
    <tp:docstring>
      A UTF-8 string indicating the type of (toolkit-specific) event being requested. Register with this application toolkit for "Accessibility.Accessible" event notifications. DEPRECATED
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="pause">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>Request that the application temporarily stop sending events.
        In most cases this should pause the application's main event loop.</p>
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="out" type="b" tp:type="boolean">
        <tp:docstring>
	    <p>True if the request succeeded, false otherwise.</p>
    
        <p>This method is not implemented in most toolkits, and therefore should be treated with caution.</p>
        </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="resume">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>Request that the application resume sending events.</p>
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="out" type="b" tp:type="boolean">
    <tp:docstring>
      True if the request succeeded, False otherwise.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="getLocale">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>Gets the locale in which the application is currently operating.
        For the current message locale, use \a lctype LOCALE_TYPE_MESSAGES.    </p>

    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="in" name="lctype" type="u" tp:type="LOCALE_TYPE">
    <tp:docstring>
      <p>The LocaleType for which the locale is queried.</p>
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="out" type="s">
    <tp:docstring>
      A string compliant with the POSIX standard for locale description.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
</interface>
</node>
