<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<node xmlns:tp="http://telepathy.freedesktop.org/wiki/DbusSpec#extensions-v0" name="/node">
<interface name="org.freedesktop.atspi.LoginHelper">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>An interface for use by assistive technologies by which
      they can access system information and services on a 'need to know'
      basis while the screen is locked, during user authentication, or
      during other sensitive operations.  </p>

    <p>This interface is intended for use by assistive technologies
      and related user-enabling services, and by applications and
      utilities which may wish to restrict access to certain system 
      devices and services during security-sensitive states, e.g. when 
      the screen is locked or during authentication into some secure
      service.  </p>

    <p>Such 'applications' (for instance, screen lock dialogs and
      security-enabled web browsers) use the LoginHelper client
      interfaces, and the bonobo-activation query service, to
      query for assistive technologies which advertise the LoginHelper
      service.  The client then queries these assistive technologies 
      for their device I/O requirements, via the getDeviceReqs call.
      The client may then issue the advisory request setSafe (TRUE), 
      which requests that the LoginHelper -implementing service make a
      best-effort attempt to make itself more secure (for instance, 
      an onscreen keyboard might turn off word prediction, and a
      screenreader may turn off keyboard echo via speech).  The return
      value of setSafe is an advisory indication of whether this attempt
      was successful (no specific guarantees are implied).
      Once the 'security sensitive' state is exited, the client should 
      call setSafe (FALSE).  </p>

    <p>The return values from getDeviceReqs inform the client of which
      services the LoginHelper service (e. g. assistive technology) needs
      in order to do its job.  The client may use this information to
      loosen any restrictions on access which it may currently have in 
      place (for instance, keyboard grabs, etc.).  If it does not do so,
      the likely outcome is that the end-user will experience loss
      of access to the system.  </p>
  </tp:docstring>
  <tp:struct name="WindowInfo">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>A structure containing info about toplevel X windows that
        the LoginHelper instance wishes to have raised.    </p>
    </tp:docstring>
    <tp:member type="i" tp:name="winID">
    </tp:member>
  </tp:struct>
  <tp:enum name="DeviceReq" type="u">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>The system and device access and services which the LoginHelper-implementing 
        assistive technology requires in order to enable the user to use the system.    </p>
    </tp:docstring>
    <tp:enumvalue suffix="GUI_EVENTS">
    <tp:docstring>
       Needs access to the GUI event subsystem (e.g. Xserver) 
    </tp:docstring>
    </tp:enumvalue>
    <tp:enumvalue suffix="CORE_KEYBOARD" value="1">
    <tp:docstring>
      Needs access to the system keyboard events (read and write) 
    </tp:docstring>
    </tp:enumvalue>
    <tp:enumvalue suffix="CORE_POINTER" value="2">
    <tp:docstring>
      Needs access to the onscreen pointer (e.g. mouse pointer) 
    </tp:docstring>
    </tp:enumvalue>
    <tp:enumvalue suffix="EXT_INPUT" value="3">
    <tp:docstring>
      Reads XInput extended input devices 
    </tp:docstring>
    </tp:enumvalue>
    <tp:enumvalue suffix="POST_WINDOWS" value="4">
    <tp:docstring>
      Posts Windows, and needs for toplevel windows to be visible 
    </tp:docstring>
    </tp:enumvalue>
    <tp:enumvalue suffix="AUDIO_OUT" value="5">
    <tp:docstring>
      Writes to audio device 
    </tp:docstring>
    </tp:enumvalue>
    <tp:enumvalue suffix="AUDIO_IN" value="6">
    <tp:docstring>
      Reads from audio device 
    </tp:docstring>
    </tp:enumvalue>
    <tp:enumvalue suffix="NETWORK" value="7">
    <tp:docstring>
      Requires access to general network services, including remote access 
    </tp:docstring>
    </tp:enumvalue>
    <tp:enumvalue suffix="LOCALHOST" value="8">
    <tp:docstring>
      Requires network services hosted on LOCALHOST only 
    </tp:docstring>
    </tp:enumvalue>
    <tp:enumvalue suffix="SERIAL_OUT" value="9">
    <tp:docstring>
      Writes to a serial port 
    </tp:docstring>
    </tp:enumvalue>
    <tp:enumvalue suffix="SERIAL_IN" value="10">
    <tp:docstring>
      !&lt;: Reads from a serial port 
    </tp:docstring>
    </tp:enumvalue>
  </tp:enum>
  <method name="setSafe">
    <tp:docstring>
      setSafe:
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="in" name="safe_mode" type="b" tp:type="boolean">
    <tp:docstring>
	    <code>True</code> if the client is requesting that 'safe mode' be initiated.
	    <code>False</code> if the client is advising that 'safe mode' may be 
	    exited. i.e. Normal operation may be resumed.
	    
	    Request a LoginHelper to enter "safe" mode, orinform LoginHelper that "safe" mode may be exited.
	    If safe_mode is <code>True</code>, but the return value is <code>False</code> ,the requesting
	    client may wish to deny services to the LoginHelper, for instance avoid raising its toplevels.
	    The return value is purely advisory, and no guarantees are intended about what the implementing 
	    LoginHelper will do to improve security when in "safe" mode.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
    <arg direction="out" type="b" tp:type="boolean">
    <tp:docstring>
      whether the LoginHelper is now "safe" or not.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="getDeviceReqs">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>Query a LoginHelper for the types of
        device I/O it requires, in order to do its job.
        For instance, a LoginHelper which needs to receive keyboard
        events will include 
        Accessibility_LoginHelper_CORE_KEYBOARD in this list.    </p>
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="out" type="u" tp:type="DeviceReqList">
    <tp:docstring>
	    A sequence of LoginHelper_DeviceReq indicatingthe device I/O required in order to facilitate end-user
	    access to the system.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="getRaiseWindows">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>Get a list of window IDs that need raising on login.</p>
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="out" type="ai" tp:type="WindowList">
    <tp:docstring>
	    A sequence containing window IDS for toplevels whichneed to be raised/made
	    visible during user authentication, inorder for the LoginHelper to facilitate
	    end-user access to the system.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
</interface>
</node>
