<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<node xmlns:tp="http://telepathy.freedesktop.org/wiki/DbusSpec#extensions-v0" name="/node">
<tp:enum name="RelationType" type="u">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>RelationType specifies a relationship between objects (possibly one-to-many or many-to-one)
      outside of the normal parent/child hierarchical relationship.  It allows better semantic
      identification of how objects are associated with one another.
      For instance the RELATION_LABELLED_BY relationship may be used to identify labelling information
      that should accompany the accessibleName property when presenting an object's content or identity
      to the end user.  Similarly, RELATION_CONTROLLER_FOR can be used to further specify the context
      in which a valuator is useful, and/or the other UI components which are directly effected by
      user interactions with the valuator. Common examples include association of scrollbars with
      the viewport or panel which they control.</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="RELATION_NULL">
  <tp:docstring>
    Not a meaningful relationship; clients should not normally encounter this RelationType value. 
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="RELATION_LABEL_FOR" value="1">
  <tp:docstring>
    Object is a label for one or more other objects. 
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="RELATION_LABELLED_BY" value="2">
  <tp:docstring>
    Object is labelled by one or more other objects. 
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="RELATION_CONTROLLER_FOR" value="3">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>Object is an interactive object which modifies the state, onscreen location, or other attributes
      of one or more target objects. </p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="RELATION_CONTROLLED_BY" value="4">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>Object state, position, etc. is modified/controlled by user interaction with one or 
      more other objects.   For instance a viewport or scroll pane may be CONTROLLED_BY scrollbars. </p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="RELATION_MEMBER_OF" value="5">
  <tp:docstring>
    Object has a grouping relationship (e.g. 'same group as') to one or more other objects.  
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="RELATION_TOOLTIP_FOR" value="6">
  <tp:docstring>
    Object is a tooltip associated with another object. 
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="RELATION_NODE_CHILD_OF" value="7">
  <tp:docstring>
    Reserved for future use. 
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="RELATION_EXTENDED" value="8">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>Used to indicate that a relationship exists, but its type is not specified in the enumeration
      and must be obtained via a call to getRelationTypeName.  </p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="RELATION_FLOWS_TO" value="9">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>Object renders content which flows logically to another object.  
      For instance, text in a paragraph may flow to another object which is not the 
      'next sibling' in the accessibility hierarchy. </p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="RELATION_FLOWS_FROM" value="10">
  <tp:docstring>
    Reciprocal of RELATION_FLOWS_TO. 
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="RELATION_SUBWINDOW_OF" value="11">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>Object is visually and semantically considered a subwindow of another object, even though
      it is not the object's child.  Useful when dealing with embedded applications and other cases
      where the widget hierarchy does not map cleanly to the onscreen presentation.  </p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="RELATION_EMBEDS" value="12">
  <tp:docstring>
    Similar to SUBWINDOW_OF, but specifically used for cross-process embedding.  
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="RELATION_EMBEDDED_BY" value="13">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>Reciprocal of RELATION_EMBEDS; Used to denote content rendered by embedded renderers that
      live in a separate process space from the embedding context.  </p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="RELATION_POPUP_FOR" value="14">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>Denotes that the object is a transient window or frame associated with another onscreen object.
      Similar to TOOLTIP_FOR, but more general.  Useful for windows which are technically 
      toplevels but which, for one or more reasons, do not explicitly cause their associated
      window to lose 'window focus'. Creation of a ROLE_WINDOW object with the POPUP_FOR relation
      usually requires some presentation action on the part of assistive technology clients, even though
      the previous toplevel ROLE_FRAME object may still be the active window.  </p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="RELATION_PARENT_WINDOW_OF" value="15">
  <tp:docstring>
    This is the reciprocal relation to RELATION_POPUP_FOR. 
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="RELATION_DESCRIPTION_FOR" value="16">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>Indicates that an object provides descriptive information 
      about another object; more verbose than RELATION_LABEL_FOR. </p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="RELATION_DESCRIBED_BY" value="17">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>Indicates that another object provides descriptive information 
      about this object; more verbose than RELATION_LABELLED_BY. </p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
  <tp:enumvalue suffix="RELATION_LAST_DEFINED" value="18">
  <tp:docstring>
    Do not use as a parameter value, used to determine the size of the enumeration. 
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:enumvalue>
</tp:enum>
</node>
