<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<node xmlns:tp="http://telepathy.freedesktop.org/wiki/DbusSpec#extensions-v0" name="/node">
<interface name="org.freedesktop.atspi.Hyperlink">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>Instances of Hyperlink are returned by Hypertext objects, and are
      the means by which end users and clients interact with linked, and in
      some cases embedded, content.  Hyperlinks may have multiple "anchors",
      where an anchor corresponds to a reference to a particular resource with
      a corresponding resource identified (URI).  Hyperlinks may be 
      queried for their URIs, or queried for the objects corresponding to their
      anchors.  The objects thus obtained are instances of Accessible,
      and may be queried, and manipulated via the Action interface.   </p>

    <p>A Hyperlink implementor is normally NOT an Accessible; 
      the preferred usage is for a Hyperlink's associated 'objects'
      (accessed via the getObject method) are Accessibles.  This means
      that Actions such as 'open link' are normally invoked on
      the result of Hyperlink.getObject rather than directly on the 
      Hyperlink instance. For historical reasons some implementors of Hyperlink
      implement Action as well.  This usage on the part of implementing
      applications and toolkits is discouraged, but clients of Hyperlink
      should be aware of it and prepared to handle such usage.</p>
  </tp:docstring>
  <tp:property name="nAnchors" type="n" access="read">
  <tp:docstring>
    The number of separate anchors associated with this Hyperlink 
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:property>
  <tp:property name="startIndex" type="i" access="read">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>The starting offset within the containing Hypertext content 
      with which this Hyperlink is associated </p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:property>
  <tp:property name="endIndex" type="i" access="read">
  <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>The ending offset within the containing Hypertext content 
      with which this Hyperlink is associated; that is, the offset of the
      first element past the range within the Hypertext associated with
      this Hyperlink. </p>
  </tp:docstring>
  </tp:property>
  <method name="getObject">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>Gets the i'th object, (where i is an integer between 0 and
        Hyperlink.numAnchors - 1, inclusive) associated with a Hyperlink.
        The objects returned are usually actionable (i.e. they should implement
        Accessibility.Action), and the available actions often include
        'open', 'bookmark', 'save link as', etc.  They may also implement
        Accessibility.StreamableContent, although clients can normally use 
        getURI to obtain a resource locator via which the object's
        data may be accessed.    </p>

      <p>The most common application for 'multi anchor'
        hyperlinks in HTML is probably 'client side imagemaps'.
        A clickable image which uses the HTML 'usemap' attribute
        should have one anchor for every area; element that
        includes an HREF.  The objects corresponding to these map
        areas may implement Accessibility.Component, to represent
        their onscreen bounding box, and may expose their 'shape' as
        as name-value pair via Accessible.getAttributeSet.</p>
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="in" name="i" type="i"/>
    <arg direction="out" type="o" tp:type="Accessible">
    <tp:docstring>
      An Accessible object instance representing theHyperlink's ith anchor, or through which the content associated with the ith anchor can beaccessed.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="getURI">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>Obtain a resource locator ('URI') which can be used to 
        access the content to which this link "points" or is connected.</p>
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="in" name="i" type="i"/>
    <arg direction="out" type="s">
    <tp:docstring>
      A string corresponding to the URI of the Hyperlink's'ith' anchor, if one exists, or a NIL string otherwise.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
  <method name="isValid">
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>Check the hyperlink to see if a connection to its backing
	 content can be established, or if its URI is valid. </p>
      <p>Instances of invalid hyperlinks include links with malformed
        URIs, or for which a contact to the service provider
        specified in the URI cannot be established.</p>
    </tp:docstring>
    <arg direction="out" type="b" tp:type="boolean">
    <tp:docstring>
	    <code>True</code> if the object's content is available, or\c False if the hyperlink's URI is invalid, or a connection to the resource can not be established.
    </tp:docstring>
    </arg>
  </method>
</interface>
</node>
